## **BERNIE TULL**

#### 18308 CRESTMOUNT ROAD, BOYDS, MD 20841

(301) 250-8311 • bernietull@outlook.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/bernietull

# **Executive Summary**

Information Technology leader with over 20 years' experience collaborating with all levels of business leadership implementing IT strategy and aligning technology projects with business objectives. Successful achievements include managing and developing staff, strategic and tactical operations, building self-service cloud infrastructure solutions, Project Management, Mobility, Security, Vendor and Contract Management.

### **Skills**

Strategic Planning | Staff Assessment and Development | ITIL | Project Management | Infrastructure Engineering and Operations | Team Building & Training | Private and Hybrid Cloud Infrastructure | Disaster Recovery | Business Continuity | HIPAA | Unified Communications | Hyper-Converged Infrastructure | Data Center | Storage Architecture and Solutions | Virtualization | Mobility | Citrix XenApp and XenDesktop | VMWare | EMC | HP | 3PAR | VDI | Cisco | BYOD | Application Delivery | Security | IaaS / PaaS / SaaS | Microsoft Active Directory, SCCM, SQL, Exchange

# **Experience**

Consultant / Project Manager = June 2016 - Current Symantec = Ashburn, VA

Partnering with GTSG to lead several teams at Symantec, one of the largest global security companies, move 40 global data centers to AWS and Azure public cloud leaving only four corporate run data centers globally. The total savings from this global data center consolidation will help Symantec save \$400 Million USD in 2 years and help Symantec more easily integrate with the recent \$4.7 Billion USD acquisition of Blue Coat.

### Active projects include:

- Trust Services PCI Remediation where we are managing, sourcing, and reporting to Executive Management on 4 simultaneous work streams to address over 200 of the most significant security control issues
- Migrating all data center services from Symantec's largest London, England based data center to their Amsterdam data center
- Working with key customer facing business units to develop Method of Procedures and Standard Operating Procedures which will allow the team to repair several remote power panels without incurring any customer facing service interruptions

# Principal Consultant Healthcare IT - September 2014 – June 2016

TEKsystems, Inc. • Vidant Health, Greenville, NC

Collaborate with Vidant Health's IT senior and executive leadership to expedite several key infrastructure projects including migrating Vidant's Novell solutions to an all Microsoft architecture.

Subject matter expert in Healthcare IT Infrastructure market working with lead consultants to develop End User Computing and Data Center strategies for Vidant Health

Work with key consultants and vendors to design a self-service infrastructure solution enabling business driven IT solutions and creating IT efficiency through orchestration and automation.

Direct cross-functional technology teams and vendors during Vidant's email migration project moving over 16,000 mailboxes from Novell GroupWise to an on-premise Microsoft Exchange 2013 enterprise solution

Direct and guide Vidant's technical teams through the migration from Novell ZENworks to Microsoft SCCM 2012 R2

Lead application and infrastructure teams to successfully move Vidant from their legacy Microsoft Active Directory solution to their newly branded and more effective Vidant Health AD architecture

Manage various technical teams through Vidant's Windows 7 and Office 2013 upgrade project for over 10,000 computers

Provide day to day operational support and leadership through Vidant's IT organizational transition assuming various roles as needed keeping teams engaged during this major organizational change

### IT Director • January 2012 – August 2014 PSI • Washington, DC

Work with IT and Executive teams to establish strategic plans for global IT applications, solutions, and services for the upcoming 5 years. Assess in detail the current IT team's responsiveness to global requirements, customer service levels, and individual skill sets. Identify opportunities for improvement and sourcing for commodity services within the headquarters office.

Worked jointly with the board of directors and organization's executives through the process of assessing and evaluating technology and related services in order to establish 3 year road map objectives

Source end to end ITIL service desk and 24x7 monitoring saving organization \$500,000 per year

Replaced entire infrastructure including network, servers, desktops, and storage solution while virtualizing over 95% of all systems

Worked with International offices located in over 70 countries across the globe to assess staffing and technology in order to address decentralization and lack of centralized management, security, and skills

Established minimum standard requirements across the organization for all technology solutions and services

Developed and reported against key performance indicators for all technology services across the global enterprise

Worked with Board of Directors Audit Committee on Disaster Recovery and Business Continuity solutions for major line of business applications utilized by all global offices

## Director Project Management • October 2010 – December 2011 DesignDATA Systems, Inc. • Gaithersburg, MD

Executive team member working with ownership to lead project management team in order to establish successful framework to direct largest global managed services client with staff in Washington, DC, Europe, and many frequent global travelers. Direct corporate management, executive team members, and implementation teams through migration to cloud and enterprise solutions.

Developed and established corporate wide standards for cloud services and solutions

Work closely with corporate leadership for large enterprise clients providing CIO / CTO services

Assess and evaluate client's corporate IT budgets, vendor's, and staff in order to propose management plans based on organizational business objectives

Collaborate with client management to establish technology steering committee solely based on non-IT business leaders

Coordinated with DesignDATA management developing standard KPI reports demonstrating standardized value for all clients

### Technology Services Director • July 1996 – September 2010 Sibley Memorial Hospital / CareTech Solutions • Washington, DC

Developed strategic plans for Information Technology initiatives to meet goals and objectives set forth by senior management. Served as a member of the Information Technology steering committee for the hospital. Successfully implemented many highly visible Information Technology projects resulting in positive return on investment. Managed daily operations of the technology service and support group within the Information Technology Department.

Lead HIPAA implementation solutions reporting to Board of Directors

Developed and implemented auditable security patch management solution

Directed technical team leads implementing Cisco Unified Communications and Infrastructure projects

Sourced key projects to vendor's while managing objectives and contracts in order to keep projects on schedule and within budget

Established corporate standards for IT steering committee in order to transition from best of breed to standards based application delivery model

## **Education**

University of Maryland University College May 1999 • Computer Information Science GPA 3.30